Stephen Bosire

ICT Support | Networking | Software Development

bossteve98@gmail.com | 0727641021

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Skilled and motivated ICT graduate with experience in ICT support ,Networking, Front end development with a solid educational background in Information and Communication Technology. Effective communicator and committed to delivering high-quality software solutions while continuously expanding knowledge and skill set in the field of IT.

EXPERIENCE

Kenya Electricity Generating Company PLC (KenGen)

Nairobi, Kenya

ICT Intern

November 2023-April 2023

- ICT service Desk and support Data backup and transfers, software installations, formatting & restoring work stations, email configuration, Upgraded the computer hardware and software while resolving their issues
- Network/Telecommunication -phones & switch configuration, video conferencing setting,Local area network maintenance
- System Administration ICT Security & backup, Mail exchange

Tropical Communication Center

Nairobi, Kenya

Cyber Attendant

Jan 2023 - Nov 2023

- Graphics design.
- Managing customer accounts and ensuring that they are billed accurately.
- Assisting customers with printing, scanning, and other computer-related tasks.
- Computer and Network troubleshooting

National Youth Fund

Nairobi, Kenya

ICT attachee

October 2021- January 2022

- Database management
- Local Area Network maintenance
- Upgraded the computer hardware and software while resolving their issues
- Provided On-site support to users on matters of ICT

STRENGTHS

- Customer Support
- Trouble shooting
- ICT support

- Computer Hardware maintenance
- Computer Networks
- Html,Css,Javascript,React,Ruby on Rails

EDUCATION

Moringa School Nairobi, Kenya

Software Development

Coursework: FullStack Software Development, Test-driven development, Javascript, React, Figma, Ruby, Ruby on Rails

Laikipia University Nyahururu, Kenya

BSc in Information and Communication Technology(ICT)

• **Coursework:** Data Structures and Algorithms, Object-oriented programming, System design and analysis, Machine learning, UI/UX, web development

KEY PROJECTS

food-for-thought Nairobi, Kenya

GitHub Link:https://github.com/bossteve1/food-for-thought

Live Site: https://food-for-thought-fawn.vercel.app/

- Technologies used: JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, MealDb API, and vercel.
- A site where a user is able to search for common recipes around the world and use them to cook any type of food. The recipes are grouped into different categories based on their origin

Movie-Review Nairobi, Kenya

GitHub Link: https://github.com/bossteve1/movie-review-app

Livesite: movie-review-app-tmiu.onrender.com

- Technologies used: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord, React, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Render
- This is a movie review app that allows users to log in and view their favorite Kenyan movies and shows and be able to review the movies and rate them. This allows the movie fans to have a say of appreciation towards the producers or even criticism.

REFEREES

- Catherine Mulwa Principal ICT Officer Kenya Electricity Generating Company PLC CMulwa@kengen.co.ke 0722570282
- Duncan Makori ICT Officer National Youth Fund 0711715849 danmoindi254@gmail.com
- 3. George Mokua Moturi
 Owner Tropical Communication Center
 0722309166